Carla Jeanpierre

Hyattsville, Maryland 20781

Phone: 347.776.2503 | Email: carlatresejeanpierre@gmail.com

 $Linked In: \underline{www.linked in.com/in/carlatrese jean pierre} \mid Git Hub: \underline{github.com/cljean pierre} \mid Portfolio: \underline{githu$

https://cljeanpierre.github.io/MyPortfolio/

Summary

Highly competent, adaptable, and hardworking software developer with a track record of teaching mathematics, editing written publications, and working with professionals in teams. An excellent communicator with a high aptitude for paying attention to details. Professionally trained in creative writing, coding, teaching, research, and analysis. Demonstrated proficiency in web development and engineering full stack applications.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Python

Applications: APIs, JSON, AJAX, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MySQL, WordPress

Development Tools: Heroku, Git, GitHub, JSLint, Jest, Mocha, Chai

Additional Areas of Expertise: Agile Development, Responsive Web Design, User Authentication,

Templating Engines, MVC, Google Analytics, Project Management

Projects

Note Taker | Link to GitHub - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/NoteTaker | Link to Deployed Project - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/NoteTaker | Link to Deployed Project - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/NoteTaker | Link to Deployed Project - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/NoteTaker | Link to Deployed Project - https://littaiga-83463. https://littaiga-8463. <a href="http

- Application that allows users to write, save, and delete notes
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Express.js, JSON, Heroku

COVID-19 Tracking App | Link to GitHub - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/Project-2 | Link to Deployed Project - https://project2qwu.herokuapp.com

- Application that tracks COVID-19 data in user's state
- Contributing Author
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, Bootstrap, API, AJAX, Heroku

Team Profile Generator |

Link to GitHub - https://github.com/cljeanpierre/Template-Engine---Employee-Summary | Link to Video Demonstration -

https://drive.google.com/file/d/14MQZ7KT2zosuHVdwBsU1x97e2cHg9si-/view

- A Node Command Line Interface records information about employees and generates an HTML webpage that reflects the information for each employee
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Templating Engines, Jest

Work Experience

AP Computer Science Tutor C2 Education

January 2022 – Present McLean, VA

Provide in-person and virtual tutoring to assist high school taking AP classes pass the exam for college credit. enhance their understanding of the Java programming language, including the basics: objects, classes, and inheritance; lists and arrays; sorting and searching; also provide tutoring in all subject areas of the SAT and ACT standardized tests

Freelance Web Consultant Literacy Partners

May 2022 – June 2022 New York, NY

Set up the domain and URL for the book launch event; set up, designed, and tested donations using Gravity Forms; tracked revenue and site traffic using Google Analytics; worked with Senior Director of Marketing to complete template design; fixed bugs and other technical issues; provided end of event closing report

Math Instructor Latin American Youth Center

June 2019 – June 2021 Washington, DC

Taught algebra and geometry to young adults seeking their high school equivalency diploma and job training as part of the Montgomery Country Conservation Corps; tracked student metrics and performance on Salesforce; developed and delivered online math curriculum

HSE Instructor and College Transition Coordinator Latin American Youth Center

January 2014 – August 2018 Brooklyn, NY

Provided instruction in algebra, geometry, and English language arts to adults seeking their high school equivalency diploma and/or documentation that correlates with international credentials; evaluated and documented students' academic performance; developed curriculum in accordance with NY State Common Core Standards; assisted students transition from adult education programs to post-secondary education and training in computer programming, nursing, and woodworking in partnership with Brooklyn Workforce Innovations and NYCHA

Education

Full Stack Coding Certificate: The George Washington University, Washington, D.C.

M.S., Education: Long Island University, Brooklyn, NY M.F.A., Creative Writing: The New School, New York, NY

B.A., Literature in English: University of California at Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Fulbright Research Fellow: Hanoi University, Hanoi, VN